Software Engineer

# **BRANT COLLINS**

Phone: (219) 331-1541

Email: brantcollins@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/brant-collins

Github: Ibrantcollins.github.io

### **Profile**

Software engineer, statistician, and teacher. As a software engineer, enjoy leveraging experience as a statistician and teacher by working in organizations that value input from their technologists about varied aspects of their digital product. Work best surrounded by smart people who generously share ideas.

### **Skills**

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEERING**

Intermediate proficiency: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, JQuery, Express with Node.js, MVC with REST, React, Python, Flask, mongoDB, SQL, Git, GitHub, and Agile workflow

# STATISTICAL PROGRAMMING

R, C, SAS, vi, LaTeX, RMarkdown **SOFT SKILLS** 

Public speaking, professional writing

### **Education**

PHD in STATISTICS
University of Chicago
BS in MATHEMATICS
University of Texas at San Antonio

### SOFTWARE ENGINEERING FELLOW

General Assembly, Chicago

## **Experience**

**SOFTWARE ENGINEERING FELLOW** – General Assembly, Chicago, 2019-present General Assembly is a global leader in technology education

- Programming: Designed and built web applications using Javascript, JQuery, HTML, and CSS.
- **Web development**: Designed and built full-stack applications using Javascript, Express with Node.js, React, Python with Flask, noSQL and SQL databases
- Version control: git and Github

**SENIOR LECTURER IN STATISTICS** – University of Chicago, 2003-2009, 2012-2019 University of Chicago is a top-tier research institution with a top-five statistics graduate studies program

- **Teaching**: Taught statistics to 2500+ diverse, high-achieving undergraduates.
- Training: Held workshops for 800+ students new to R and RMarkdown
- Mentoring: Guided new lecturers and graduate student instructors.
- Advising: Offered course and degree plan advising to statistics majors, minors, and non-majors.
- Data analysis: Programmed in R, C, and SAS. Wrote reports using LaTeX and Markdown.

**RESEARCHER AND STATISTICIAN** – Chapin Hall at the University of Chicago, 2009-2012 Chapin Hall is a research and policy think tank for issues relating to the welfare of children and families

- **Risk analysis**: Wrote SQL queries and SAS programs to analyze and present data for researchers and policy makers regarding the experiences of over 1.5 million children in foster care in 26 states.
- **Professional writing**: Co-authored or contributed to the methodology sections of white papers, policy proposals, and peer-reviewed research.
- **Public speaking**: Delivered talks on statistical analyses and their results to technical and non-technical audiences of sizes 10 to 300.

### **Other Tech Interests**

Collins family tech guru: Act as the family tech help desk -- building desktops, doing complete tear-downs of laptops to replace that noisy fan or cracked screen, advising on tech purchases, etc.